ラジオや会話 ハートでつかめ 英語の極意 講師の大西 博人です
さあ 金曜復習会 頑張っていきましょう
Hey everyone, this is Akino Rosa. Welcome to Friday's review lesson. Let's get started.
And I'm David Evans. It's review time. Woohoo!
それでは早速始めていきましょう
Lesson 110
今週のリビュー 金曜日は復習会です
最初のコーナーはこちら
リスニングチャレンジ
OK
Let's review this week's dialogues
Listen to the questions
and pick which one of the three options
is the correct answer
Let's start with Monday's dialogue
OK guys, here's the question
Why are the fans happy?
A. Derek is coming back to the band
B. Derek decided to leave the band again
or C. Derek is coming back to the band
デリックが世界で最高のベースプレーヤーになった
行きましょう
ビル、デリックがバンドに戻ってくれるのに 嬉しいのかい?
うーん、気分が悪い
なぜ?
デリックが最初に帰ることを決めたから
今は彼の思いを変えた
ファンは嬉しい
大丈夫だよ。間違いない
デリックイズグレイベースプレイヤー
ウィジェスディスグリードオンオーロンオフテインス
サチャース
ドーンゲーミースタート
ユガイスウォールケイダースタイムゴースバイ
アムシュアブイ
ニャープロブブリ
オケイエブリオン
ディジュゲットア
レッツゴーフォーザクエッション
ワンモアタイム
ワイアー
ドファンズ
ハピ
エイ
デリックイズ
カミングバック
ドゥ
バンド
ビー
derek decided to leave the band again or c derek became the greatest bass player in the world
答えは a derek is coming back to the band 質問はファンたちはどうして喜んでいる
a デレクがバンドに戻ってくるから b デレクがバンドをまた辞めると決めたから
c デレクが世界で最も優秀なベース奏者になったから
答えはA デレクがバンドに戻ってくるからとなります
Movin' right along, here's Tuesday's dialogue
First, let's check out the question
What does Estella want Akira not to do?
A. Contact Omega-3
B. Jump onto the spaceship
C. Talk to anyone about the problem
Listen up
秋田 we have a problem
what's wrong is the love
we've lost contact with omega 3
megan is on that ship
i know we're doing everything we can
maybe there was some accident up in space
let's not jump to any conclusions
when did you lose contact
it happened suddenly about an hour ago
we need to handle this matter with care
don't say anything about this to anyone yet akira
all right
I hope they're okay.
How did you do?
Alright, let's check out the question one more time.
What does Estella want Akira not to do?
A. Contact Omega-3
B. Jump onto the spaceship
or C. Talk to anyone about the problem
答えは?
C. Talk to anyone about the problem
質問は?
エステラがアキラにしてほしくないことは
A. オメガ3に連絡を取る
B. 宇宙船に飛び乗る
C. その問題について誰かと話す
答えはC. その問題について誰かと話すとなります
次は Wednesday's Dialogue
質問です
男は何をしているのか
A. 男は何をしているのか
B. タブレットを設定し
B. タイピングを練習し
C. パスワードを覚える
気をつけなさい
イヤヨイ、新しいタブレットを設定しているのか?
はい、昨日設定したのです
問題はありますか?
はい、私に手伝ってもいいですか?
はい、まず、キーパードを使ってパスワードを入れる必要があります
私は試してみましたが、できなかったです
I don't want to spend all morning setting it up.
Take it easy. Did you type it in right? Try again.
It's the password on this slip of paper, right?
Yes. And it's case sensitive.
It worked! Okay, next step.
How'd you do? Let's check out the question one more time.
What is the man doing?
A.
setting up his tablet b practicing his typing or c trying to remember his password
答えは a setting up his tablet 質問は男性は何をしている
a タブレットの設定をしている b タイピングの練習をしている
c パスワードを思い出そうとしている 答えは a タブレットの設定をしているとなります
OK, we've got one more. That's Thursday's Dialogue. Let's check out the question.
Why was Paul disappointed?
A. Because Paul had to leave the band.
B. Because Bill didn't make a farewell speech.
C. Because Paul didn't introduce himself.
Here we go.
So, you're the new manager of the band?
はい。私の名前はステイシー。ステイシー・リーです。
ステイシーに会えることは素晴らしいです。私はデリック・シミンズです。
自分を紹介する必要はありません。あなたは有名です。
まあ、ベースプレーヤーの中ではあるかもしれません。
ベースプレーヤーについて、彼は最後の一日はどうでしたか?
彼はバンドを少し失望させました。
なぜ彼は失望させたのですか?
まあ、彼はビルをお別れの言葉をすることを期待していたのですが、ビルはそうはなかったのです。
ああ、ええ、ビルは長いグッバイが嫌いです。
はい、わかりましたか?
もう一度、質問を見てみましょう。
ポールはなぜ失敗したのですか?
A. ポールはバンドを離れてしまったからです。
B. ビルはフェアウェルスピーチをしていなかったからです。
C. ポールは自分を紹介しなかったからです。
答えは?
B. ビルはフェアウェルスピーチをしていなかったからです。
質問はポールはなぜがっかりした a ポールがバンドを辞めなければいけなかったから
b ビルがお別れのスピーチをしなかったから c ポールが自己紹介をしなかったから
答えは b ビルがお別れのスピーチをしなかったからとなります さあリスニングチャレンジできはいかがでしたでしょうか
せい イングリッシュ
今週 練習 し た 表現 を 使っ て 会話 の 実践 練習 を し ましょう
ok here's the first situation
imagine this
難しい 試験 に 合格 し た 次男
家 に 帰っ て き た 長男 が 彼 は 合格 し た の と 尋ね ます 応答 し て ください
例えば
その 通り 彼 は 部屋 で テレビ ゲーム を やっ て 楽しん で い ます よ
彼 の こと は 放っ て おい て あげ
厳しい試験の後、やっとリラックスしているの、など。
3ヒントを差し上げておきましょう。
テレビゲーム、これはビデオゲーム、どうしちゃってみてください。
もう一度セチュエーションを確認します。
難しい試験に合格した次男。
家に帰ってきた長男が、彼は合格したの?と尋ねます。
応答してください。
例えば、その通り。
彼は部屋でテレビゲームをやって楽しんでいますよ 彼のことは放っておいてあげていい
彼は厳しい試験の後やっとリラックスしているの など
さあ長男にこう聞かれますよ he passed the exam あなたならどう言いますか
それではここでローザさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認しましょう
That's right. He's having a good time playing video games in his room.
2分目はis having a good time or playing video games in his roomが説明
何々しながら楽しんでいる
leave him alone ok
he's finally relaxing after a tough exam
leave 誰々 alone は誰々を放っておく
目的語説明型の品用文ですね
それではローザさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう
that's right
He's having a good time playing video games in his room.
Leave him alone, okay?
He's finally relaxing after a tough exam.
では、今の答えを一文ずつリピートしましょう。
That's right.
He's having a good time playing video games in his room.
Leave him alone, okay?
He's finally relaxing after a tough exam.
Alright, let's move on to the next situation.
Imagine this.
友人との飲み会
あなたが車で会場に来たのを見て友人が心配しています。
応答してください。
例えば、
やあ、そう、車で来たんだ。すぐにここに来たかったんだよ。
でも問題ないよ 妻が後でみんなに挨拶しにここに来て彼女の運転で家に帰るんだよ
など さあヒントを差し上げておきましょう
誰々に挨拶をするこれはsay hi to というフレーズが使えます
誰々を車で家に送り届けるこれは drive 誰々 home というフレーズが使えます
やあ そう車で来たんだ
すぐにここに来たかったんだよでも問題ないよ 妻が後でみんなに挨拶しにここに来て彼女の運転で家に帰るんだよ
なだ さあ友人たちにこう聞かれますよ
あなたならどう言いますか
それではここでデイビッドさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認しましょう
は車で方法を表すby
2分目のquickはget hereの説明
早くここに来る
my wife will come here later to say hi to everyone
and she'll drive us home
to 付てしto say hi to everyone
は目的を表しています
それではデイビッドさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう
hi yeah i came by car
では、今の答えを一文ずつリピートしましょう。
But it's not a problem.
My wife will come here later to say hi to everyone, and she'll drive us home.
先生、行ってくるよ。
Leave him alone, okay?
He's having a good time playing video games in the studio,
finally relaxing after a long day recording.
ということで、バイ!